simplyswim.com 2013-05-26

# Website Privacy Policy

##  Privacy Policy

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected and any information we hold is secure. This policy explains how we collect, use and store your personal information.  
We are registered with the ICO (Information Commissioners Office) under the Data Protection Act 1998 - Registration Number Z7449228.

When you buy goods or services from us we need to know some basic information about you to fulfil your order. This includes (but may not be limited to) your name, address, e-mail, phone number and payment details. This information is provided by you during the checkout process and will be securely stored so that we can process your order. We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent.

We gather this information to allow us to process any orders you make and, if you have requested us to, to send you our newsletter. The relevant information is then used by us, our agents and sub-contractors to provide you with statements of your account and to communicate with you on any matter relating to the conduct of your account and the provision of the goods or services ordered. 

We may also use aggregate information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring website usage in order to help us develop our website, our range of products and our services and we may provide such aggregate information to third parties. These statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual. 

From time to time we may provide your information to our customer service agencies for research and analysis purposes so that we can monitor and improve our goods or the services we provide. We or our agents and sub-contractors may contact you by post, e-mail or telephone to ask you for your feedback and comments on our goods or services. 

We may also wish to provide you with information about special features of our website or any other service or products we think may be of interest to you. We will gain your consent to receiving this information in advance and you can easily remove yourself from future mailings by following the instructions on the bottom of the first mail you will receive.

Except as otherwise stated in this policy we will never provide your information to any third party company, unless you have expressly permitted us to do so.

###  Sale of business

If our business is sold or integrated with another business your details may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchasers and their advisers and will be passed on to the new owners of the business. 

###  Updating your details

We wish to only maintain accurate and up to date information on you. You can check and amend all the information we currently hold about you by logging into your account and make any necessary changes or from the UK call us on 0844 567 7070 or internationally on +44 1795 597250. 

###  Your consent

By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set out in this privacy policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page and may place notices on other pages of the website. Use of the service will signify that you agree to any such changes.

Owing to the global nature of the Internet infrastructure, the information you provide may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area that do not have similar protections in place regarding your data and its use as set out in this policy. However, we have taken the steps outlined above to safeguard the security of your information. By submitting your information you consent to these transfers. 

###  How to contact Us

We welcome your views about our website and our privacy policy. If you would like to contact us with any queries or comments please send an e-mail to CustomerCare@TheSimplyGroup.com or from the UK call us on 0844 567 7070 or internationally on +44 1795 597250.

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

**Information** | **Why do we to need know this?** | **Who do we share this information with?**  
---|---|---  
**Name and address details  
** | So we know where to send your order.  | The courier who delivers your order. 

Partners and 3rd party service providers are prohibited from sharing your information except where required to do so by law. Certain shipment data will be provided by the courier to the authorities of the country of transit or destination for customs and tax clearance or for security screening, as required by the laws of such country. The information provided would usually include: shipper name and address, receiver name and address, description of the goods, number of pieces, weight and value of shipment.   
  
  | So we can perform security checks against your payment method. | Our bank and your card issuer  
**E-mail address** | So that we can let you know the status of your order. | Only us.  
  | If you have requested notification of when a specific item comes in to stock. | Only us.  
  | To let you know when your delivery is due, our chosen courier may email you with an estimated time and date of delivery. | The courier company chosen to deliver your order. Partners and 3rd party service providers are prohibited from sharing your information except where required to do so by law.  
  
  | To ask you to review your shopping experience and products purchased.  
| Chosen review service provider. Partners and 3rd party service providers are prohibited from sharing your information except where required to do so by law.  
  
  | If you have requested our offers and newsletter. | Your email address is shared in the form of a distribution list with an email marketing service. Partners and 3rd party service providers are prohibited from sharing your information except where required to do so by law.  
**Phone number** | So that we can keep in touch regarding your order. | Only us.  
  | To let you know when your delivery is due, our chosen courier may text you with an estimated time and date of delivery.  
| The courier company chosen to deliver your order. Partners and 3rd party service providers are prohibited from sharing your information except where required to do so by law.  
  
**Payment card details** | So we can take the funds to pay for your order | Our bank and your card issuer via secure encrypted payment processing gateway. We are fully PCI DSS Compliant (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard).  
**Order details** | Details about what you order will be stored for a minimum of six years so that we can assist you should you need to contact us about your order in the future. | Only us.  
  
## Cookies, what are they and how do we use them?

Cookies are small text files placed on your computer or mobile device that help the website remember your device. They are used for a few different purposes and can stay on your device for different lengths of time, below is a guide to what cookies we use and what they are for. 

##  Session Cookies 

**Without these our website won't work properly**

Session cookies are used to remember what is in your shopping basket and what stage you are at in the checkout process. Session cookies expire and are deleted automatically after you close your browser or end your session. 

Accepting these cookies is a condition of using the websites. You can chose to restrict these cookies if you wish, however the site will not function correctly.

Below is a list of the Session cookies we use.

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose** | **Provider**  
---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId | Remembers what is in your shopping basket. | Us  
State | Remembers what stage your order is at. | Us  
  
## Function and Analytics Cookies 

**These cookies help improve your visit experience**

These cookies are used to enable specific functionality i.e. the live chat facility or product advice videos, as well as help us improve the site by measuring any errors and analyse how visitors choose to use the site. These cookies share information with our partners to provide a service on our website and expire after 30 days. 

These cookies cannot be used to identify who you are and will not be used to target you with adverts on other websites.

You can choose to restrict these cookies; however it may reduce the functionality and your experience of the site.

Below is a list of the function and analytics cookies we use and who provides them.

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose** | **Provider**  
---|---|---  
Source | Remembers which affiliate site your visit came from | Us  
HumanClickACTIVE  
HumanClickKEY  
HumanClickSiteContainerID_ | Enables live chat Customer Services support. | Live Person  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE | Enables you to view video content hosted by YouTube on our sites. | YouTube  
_utmc  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmz | Helps us analyse how the site is used and improve our site performance. | Google Analytics   
  
## Social Media and Tracking Cookies

**These cookies are for social media and advertising**

These cookies are generally associated with 'Like', 'Share' or 'Add' buttons from third party social media providers. In return for 'sharing' with your social network, the service provider remembers your visit to our site and uses this to build a profile of your interests. 

The information collected by these cookies may then be used by the third party provider to serve you with tailored advertising on other websites.

You can choose to restrict these cookies; however this may prevent us from providing you with some services.

Below is a list of third party, social media and tracking cookies we use and who provides them.

**Cookie Name** | **Purpose** | **Provider**  
---|---|---  
datr  
lsd  
reg_ext_ref  
reg_fb_gate  
reg_fb_ref | Enables you to share via Facebook | Facebook  
_pinterest_sess  
csrftoken | Enables you to share via Pinterest | Pinterest  
test_cookie  
id | Helps advertising be more relevant to you. | Double Click by Google  
pid  
k | Enables you to share via Twitter  | Twitter  
  
##   
How we protect your information

###  Data encryption

When you send us your information over the internet this is done using our secure pages (https://www.... ) using 128bit encrypted Secure Socket Layer (SSL) to keep your information confidential. SSL is a commonly used protocol for managing security over the internet and is the industry standard.

###  Secure Storage

Any sensitive data i.e. payment card details, that we need to store is encrypted and stored in physically secure locations. We use highly sophisticated Firewalls to prevent infection from viruses and to block penetration attempts.

###  Payment Card Industry, Data Security Standards (PCI DSS)

In accordance with PCI DSS our websites and servers are scanned regularly by Security Metrics for security weaknesses and vulnerabilities. This ensures that high security standards are maintained, which significantly reduces the risk that data will be compromised, stolen or misused.

Further information on the Data Protection Act 1998 can also be found on the Information Commissioner's website at http://www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk

Use of this website is subject to our Terms and Conditions. 

Data Protection registration number Z7449228.
